Everyone these days is using MCP
servers, but almost no one knows how to
actually build and ship production ready
MCPs. And that's what we're going to
dive into in this video from scratch.
And I'm going to make it surprisingly
straightforward with a template that you
can use right now. When Enthropic
launched the model context protocol last
November, it was genuinely impressive.
Finally, a way for us to connect our AI
agents to our external tools. It is the
way to give our agents and also our
coding assistants like cursor and claude
code superpowers by connecting them to
our systems and data. And MCP really
blew up starting March of this year.
Everyone was and still is paying
attention to it and it's getting adopted
all over the place. But when it first
blew up, there was still a huge problem
with it. It was essentially still a toy.
security vulnerabilities, no
authentication, documentation was
lacking at best, and there was no way to
deploy remote MCP servers. When you
wanted to run one yourself, you had to
actually download and host the MCP
server on your own computer. But my
friend, that is all changed now. While
everyone has been focusing on cloud code
right now, and for good reason,
Anthropic has been quietly building out
the production infrastructure for MCP
that we have all been waiting for. They
have streamable HTTP as a new transport
for the protocol that actually scales.
They're implementing OOTH, so we have
real authorization and authentication to
secure our MCP servers. They have a
bunch of documentation around security
best practices now. And we have
enterprisegrade remote MCP deployments
with platforms like Cloudflare that
actually make it really straightforward.
So, Anthropic is really pushing MCP far.
And let me just say they have been
crushing it recently with Claude, Cloud
Code, and MCP. Right now, I'm going to
show you exactly how to build
productionready MCP servers from the
ground up. This is the future of how
we're going to be powering all of our AI
agents. And it starts with this super
comprehensive template that I have
created for you. This is what we're
going to be covering today. and I follow
all the best practices here for ways to
add tools into our MCP server to handle
authentication and monitoring and
security and deployments. This isn't
just a tutorial. This is a complete
blueprint for you to take and use to
build any MCP server that you want.
We're going to build it together, then
we'll deploy it to Cloudflare, and then
I'll even show you how you can use AI
coding assistance to use this as a
starting point to build anything that
you want. I'm really excited for this.
So, let's go ahead and get right into
it. So, what we're going to be building
in this video is a TypeScript MCP server
that has authentication built in with
GitHub OOTH. We'll also be integrating
with Sentry so we can monitor our MCP in
production. And we'll deploy it to
Cloudflare. Cloudflare is not sponsoring
this video or anything. They're just the
go-to platform for deploying remote
MCPs. And I've gotten a lot of requests
to cover them specifically. So, finally,
here it is. Also, we'll be supporting
the new streamable HTTP transport layer
and then for legacy purposes supporting
SSE. And then just to have a very simple
but still practical demo for this
template, we're building a basic MCP
server that works with our Postgress
database. It's kind of like a chat with
your database MCP server. So, you just
have to give the connection details for
your Postgress account. We'll get into
that in a bit. And then we have these
three tools. One where we can list all
of the tables that are in our database.
We have another one to execute readonly
queries on our database and then another
one to execute write operations. And
this is where GitHub ooth comes in
because we're going to have
authorization protecting this MCP tool
specifically. So only a specific set of
GitHub users can even see and use this
tool. And the reason that we're building
this as a TypeScript MCP server is
because TypeScript is becoming the go-to
language for building MCPs. I haven't
covered TypeScript enough on my channel
and also it is the best programming
language to use to build remote MCPs
that we want to deploy to Cloudflare.
And getting this template up and running
yourself is very straightforward. There
are just four prerequisites that we have
here. First, you'll have to install
Node.js. Then you'll need a Cloudflare
account. You can just use the free tier.
This will work for this entire demo. So,
you just go to cloudflare.com, create a
free account. Everything in this entire
video is free, by the way. And then
you'll need a GitHub account for OOTH.
and then obviously a Postgress database
for this specific MCP server. Once you
have all those prerequisites in place,
then you can install the Wrangler CLI.
This is how we can work with Cloudflare
in the command line in our computer. So,
it's just mpm install-g for global
wrangler. And then you run the Wrangler
login command. This will direct you to
Cloudflare in your browser to
authenticate. So, now your CLI is
authenticated with your new Cloudflare
account. And then the last thing that
you have to do is just clone this
repository. Okay, so you just go up
here, get clone, and then this is your
URL. And then you can run the mpm
install command to install all of the
dependencies here for our Wrangler
Cloudflare worker project. And then you
are good to go. So before we dive into
the main MCP server implementation for
this video, there's one more thing that
I do not want to miss with you because
we need to set a solid foundation here,
understanding how MCP works at a core
level. And so I have a basic example in
this repo that I want to cover first.
Then we'll add in the extra layers of
complexity for things like
authorization, monitoring, and deploying
to Cloudflare. In this basic example, I
have based a lot on the documentation
that we have here in the GitHub page for
the TypeScript MCP SDK. So, I'll link to
this in the description as well as the
primary template that I have for you.
Really, everything that I'm covering in
this video, I'll link in the
description. So, there's just a gold
mine of resources for you. But this is
really important. We don't want to miss
the core of what makes an MCP server. So
with TypeScript, we want to import MCP
server and then also the transport layer
that we're using. Like they're using
standard IO in this case for a very
basic example. Obviously, we're going to
be upgrading to using streamable HTTP
and SSE. That's more what you need for
remote MCP. But anyway, we create an
instance of our server and then we can
register tools. That's what we'll be
focusing on in this video. These are all
the functionalities that our server
exposes. And then you can also do other
things like sampling and resources.
There's a lot of different components to
an MCP server. And then you just define
the transport that you want. And then
you spin up your server. And that's it.
You now essentially have an API
endpoint, but instead of it being for a
website, it's for an AI agent. And
that's really important to keep in mind.
It's like everything that we're building
here is not new. And the best practices
around security, it's not new. It's all
just APIs, but repackaged in a standard
for AI agents specifically. That's all
MCP is. But even though that's all it
is, it still is very powerful. So that
is our quick start and that's what I
want to show you here. So I have the
repo for our template cloned locally.
And then we have this simplemath.ts.
This is the very basic MCP server that
is adjusted to work with Cloudflare. And
then we'll build on top of this to make
our full implementation. So the
agent/mcp,
this is actually an import from
Cloudflare. It's their agents offering.
So we use this to build the main class
for our MCP server. Then we define a
server just like we saw in the GitHub
page. And then we initialize all of our
tools. So it's just this.server.tool.
We give the tool a name. We define the
arguments as well. You can also give a
description to help the AI agent know
when and how to use a tool. We'll cover
that later as well. And then the
function definition itself is what is
going to run whenever our AI agent or
coding assistant or whatever invokes the
tool in this MCP server. So this is a
very basic implementation where it's
just a tool that we can pass in numbers
that we want to add, subtract, multiply
or divide. And then towards the bottom
here, we're going to serve this MCP
server both with SSE for legacy
purposes. And then also /mcp just the
regular.serve. This is for streamable
HTTP the new transport that we have. So
with that, now going back to our readme,
all we have to do, assuming you already
have Wrangler set up with these steps,
is you just have to run the Wrangler dev
command specifying the configuration for
our MCP server, our simple version. So
you just run this command in the
directory where you cloned this
repository. And then boom, our MCP
server is now up and running, ready to
be connected from any MCP client,
cursor, cloud code, cloud desktop,
anything. And I'll even show you an
example right now with cloud desktop.
So, I've got my cloud desktop up. You
can see that I have the math MCP server
with my calculate tool. And the only
thing I had to do to set this up is go
to the top left, file, settings,
developer. This is where you enter in
your configuration for MCP. So, you just
click on edit config. This will bring
you to a folder that'll look like this.
And then you can open up cloud desktop
config. So, I'm going to open this up. I
have a bunch of new lines here. So, you
can't see my secret keys and my other
MCPs. But to connect to this one, we
just do npxmcp
remote and then it is going to be our
localhost 8789 because that is the URL
that we have this running in right now
because we want to use streamable HTTP
that is going to be our /mcp endpoint.
So this is how we connect to our MCP
server. Now we can test this out. So
I'll close out of this. You have to
restart your cloud desktop by the way
once you add in the configuration. And
now I can say use the calculate tool to
calculate. And then I'll just do a
random number multiplied by a random
number. And so I'm being explicit here
just because I want to make sure it's
using the tool. But I'll send this in.
And now Claw Desktop will ask for
permission to use our custom MCP server.
In my case, I already approved this
before, but it'll ask you for
permission. And there we go. It used the
calculate tool. We have the two numbers
multiplied together. There is our
response. So this is looking really,
really good. That is MCP at a very high
level. Now, let's start adding in the
fun stuff for GitHub authentication,
security, monitoring, you know the
drill. So, here is the game plan just so
you know the exact order of things here.
I'm going to start by showing you how to
get this MCP server up and running
yourself. It's very easy. Then, we'll
dive into how everything works. I've got
some key resources to share with you as
well. Then, we'll deploy everything to
Cloudflare so we have a production
environment for our MCP. And then last
but not least, like I promised in the
intro, we'll show you how to use AI
coding assistant. So you can literally
take this template, give it to an AI
coding assistant, and have it build any
MCP server for you that you want. And so
at this point, you already have Wrangler
installed and configured. You've got the
packages installed, you got the repo
cloned. Now we can move on to setting up
our environment variables. And so you
just have to make a copy of this file
and rename it to.dev.vars.
This is just like aenv, but more
specific to Cloudflare workers. And
there are only four environment
variables that we have to set up. At
first we need our GitHub client ID and
secret encryption key and then your
database URL which depending on your
platform this can really be any
Postgress platform. It can be superbase
neon you could host Postgress yourself.
Just get your connection string for this
environment variable. And specifically
the way that you get your GitHub ooth
app is within GitHub you just go to your
settings in the top right go down to
developer settings and click on ooth
apps. You can make a new app here and
this will then give you your client ID
and secret. So very easy to get that set
up. This is for the authentication for
our MCP. A very important component. And
then for the encryption key, you can
just set this to whatever value you
want. Very easy to get all that set up.
And then we'll cover sentry towards the
end to add monitoring for our MCP in
production. And that is it. That is
everything. And now we can go ahead and
run the Wrangler dev command to get our
MCP server up and running. And so it's
going to be very similar to the simple
example that we already covered. So I
did that on purpose so everything will
start to look very familiar for you. So
we're running kind of a simulated
version of our production environment
here. So we're running a Cloudflare MCP
server, remote MCP, but it is just
running in our terminal here on our
local machine. And the port is different
from the simple example. And so you just
have to go back into your cloud desktop
config or the config for whatever MCP
client you're using like cursor or cloud
code and just change the port to 8788.
And then you want to restart your MCP
client. And so that's what I already did
with cloud desktop. And now within here
we have our new MCP server. So I should
probably rename this from math. But
anyway, clicking into here, we now have
our three database tools that we have
for Postgress. And so I can ask a
question like what tables are in my DB?
And then when I do this right now, I've
already gone through the GitHub OOTH
process and approve this tool usage. But
for you, what's going to happen here is
it's going to actually open up a page in
your browser to sign in with GitHub
before you use this MCP. That is the
beauty is we have this gateway now to
our MCP server with GitHub
authentication. And the world is your
oyster for the way that you can protect
your MCP server now that we have
authentication in front of it. And so
I'll show a couple of screenshots here
what that actually looks like to go
through that flow. Then we go back to
claude code where we have what we're
looking at here where it says I have 19
tables in my database. And this is
looking really really good. And we can
even test another one here. I'll say
what records are in my users profiles
table. And so this will query a specific
table here. I'll give it a second to run
this. There we go. So select star from
user profiles. Looking really good. And
I just have three records right now with
just the test accounts that I have
created in this superbase. This isn't my
production superbase or anything. So
yeah, there we go. This is working so so
well. So now let's get into how I built
this MCP server, all the best practices
that go into it. Starting with the
resource that I used as the beginning
point for creating this template for you
because Cloudflare in their AI repo.
They have this demo here, building a
remote MCP server with GitHub OOTH. This
is a fantastic resource that got me
started. Like I said, I'll have a gold
mine of resources in the description.
So, this will be linked in the
description as well as some other really
helpful docs from Cloudflare on building
a remote MCP server. And then also they
have a section specifically on
authorization, which this is awesome to
check out if you want to extend past
GitHub and add an authorization for
other providers as well like Google or
X. So, these are great resources. And
then last but not least, I want to talk
about the security checklist for MCP.
So, this is what I used to determine all
the best practices that I needed to
follow to build my MCP server. And so,
super pro tip here, you can take this
resource, again, linked in the
description. You can go through this
checklist, copy everything here, and
literally just paste it in as a part of
your prompt to your AI coding assistant
when you want it to build an MCP server.
You want it to follow these things. And
that's what I did. And you can maybe
take out some of these things that might
not apply to your server. Like not
everything here is going to be super
applicable, but this is a really good
starting point to just open your eyes to
all of the security practices that are
important not just for MCP servers, but
really any back-end infrastructure. I
mean, really, like I said, MCP servers
are just APIs, but for agents. And so,
yeah, this is just really important to
follow this. And so, that's what I did.
There's quite a few rules here, but it
all boils down into what I have at the
top of the readme here. So we want our
database integration with a lifespan.
The security checklist talks a lot about
lifespan so we can manage resources like
database connections in our server and
close those down gracefully. We want
modular singlepurpose tools so the LLM
doesn't get confused when it's using our
MCP server and descriptions are very
important for that. We'll talk about
that in a bit. We want role-based access
using GitHub OOTH in our case,
especially protecting those more
sensitive tools like executing any write
query in our database. And then security
best practices, things like validating
and sanitizing the SQL queries that we
run with this server, monitoring in
production with Sentry is huge. And then
having a cloud platform to deploy the
remote MCP to that is good for scaling.
That's why we're picking Cloudflare
workers in our case. So these are the
key practices that I'm following here.
And I'll walk through our server very
quickly here. And I'll just point out
when each of these apply. And what we're
about to see here, a lot of it looks
very similar to the simple example that
we already went over. I did that very
much on purpose just to kind of ease you
in to all these other layers that we're
adding in for things like authorization,
getting things ready to deploy to
Cloudflare as well. And so, first of
all, we have this list at the top, all
of the allowed GitHub users that can use
that more sensitive write query tool.
And obviously in production, if you want
to go past a demo, you'd want to have
this list somewhere in a database. I'm
just using this for simplicity purposes
here. But it's the same kind of deal.
We're using the MCP agent that we're
importing from the Cloudflare agents
package, setting up our server, and then
as a part of our lifespan, we want to
close our database down gracefully
whenever we exit the server so we don't
have memory leaks. And so the way that
this works is when we start up our
server, and I'll show you this here.
When we start up our server, we're going
to get an instance of our database.
We're going to use that throughout the
lifespan of our MCP. And this is
something I see people just miss all of
the time. Lifespans are so important.
Definitely one of the things that's
covered in the security checklist. They
call it a life cycle management, but
then they have the whole concept of
shutting down, cleaning up resources
like our database. That's what we're
doing here. So, we get the database
instance. This is what we use throughout
the lifespan of our server. And then
we're going to clean up when our server
closes. And then when we initialize our
tools, this is where we get into tool
descriptions. So what we're looking at
right here, this is actually used as a
part of the prompt to our large language
model that is leveraging this MCP
server. That is so important to keep in
mind. This context is key for the agent
to know when and how to use this tool.
So make sure that you have a nice clear
and concise description for every single
one of the tools in your MCP server.
Then we're getting our single database
instance. This is our tool to list all
the tables we have in our DB. And then
we're also returning a very nicely
formatted string here with all the
information that we got back from that
query. So that's yet another thing is
like this information goes back to your
LLM. So you want to treat it with
respect. Make sure that it's formatted
very nicely. And we're doing this in
JSON here. And then for our other tools,
very similar. This is our one to execute
readonly SQL queries. And this is an
example of implementing security best
practices. So we're validating our SQL
query. And I'll show you what that looks
like. We're looking for dangerous
patterns and we're failing the tool call
if we find any of these. So this is just
a simple example the kinds of things
that you want to be thinking about when
implementing security for your MCP
servers and like I said really any kind
of backend infrastructure that you're
making and you want to make sure that AI
coding assistants are following these
kinds of things as well as you're using
them to build these servers. And so I'm
going to scroll down here skip past the
rest of that tool. This is where we get
into GitHub authorization. So when we
have GitHub ooth set up in our server
and we'll see what that looks like
towards the end of this file. We have
this value here, this.props.login.
This has all the information about our
user and the login specifically gives us
their GitHub username. So we can check
to make sure that they're in this list
of allowed users. If they are, then we
expose this tool. Otherwise, we're not
even going to make this tool as an
option for the user when they are using
the server through their MCP client. But
if they are allowed, then we have this.
We're validating the SQL query again.
We're executing that, making sure that
it's a safe operation, and then
returning the results of executing that
query. And we're adding error handling
with these catch blocks into all of our
tools as well. You want to make sure
that you handle errors gracefully, maybe
even having the MCP server return an
error message so the agent can
communicate back to the user and say
what exactly went wrong. So that is
everything for our tools. Then at the
very end here, we're using this OOTH
provider that we are importing from
Cloudflare. So, one of the beauties of
Cloudflare, they're not just making it
easy for us to scale and deploy our MCP
server. They actually handle the server
side of the authentication as well.
There's a lot more logic that we would
have to implement if we weren't using
Cloudflare's OOTH provider. So, there's
still some of the client side stuff that
we have to implement here. And you can
look into this if you're curious. You
could also change this to work with
something like Google Oath instead. In
our case though, we just have that set
up for the GitHub client side and then
the server is handling the rest. And so
we have our API handlers. We have one
for SSE. And then we have one for
streamable HTTP. And then we have an
authorize and register endpoints here.
You can follow the Cloudflare
documentation to know how to set all
this up. And then we have our GitHub
handler. That is all the client side
OOTH logic that we have. And then we
have our token endpoint to end things
off. So that is everything for GitHub
authentication. It is that easy to get
things set up. And you can always use an
AI coding assistant. If you want to
point it to this and then point it to
the GitHub handler and say just change
this for Google or change this for X,
you can definitely do that. And then the
very last thing going back to the readme
here, the very last thing that I want to
cover before we deploy is monitoring.
And so this I've kind of made this an
optional thing. So Centry is actually
sponsoring this video. They're
partnering with me to show you how to
monitor MCP servers in production. But I
wanted to cover this anyway. And Century
really is the best platform. It's really
the only one that I know of that makes
it super easy to integrate application
monitoring with MCP server specifically.
It's so cool because if I go into my
dashboard here, all you have to do is go
to centry.io, the free tier works for
this by the way, you have to just make a
new project and specifically the project
type. If I click on create new project,
you just want to search for Cloudflare
workers JavaScript. That's the type that
you create for Sentry. You'll get that
DSN which you use as your environment
variable. And then we can start seeing
traces come through like it use my list
tables for my MCV. So I can click into
this and I can see the logs and all the
metadata that happened with this query.
I can see the duration if there are any
errors that come up. I'm also going to
get an email like you can see right
here. This is just an example of the
email you get. So you have alerting
setup for when things fail. It is really
powerful to have this kind of monitoring
in a production environment especially
once we deploy things to Cloudflare. So
super important. If you want to set up
Sentry, all you have to do is add in
this environment variable, the DSN, and
you just get that from your Sentry
dashboard once you sign up with the free
tier. And then you just want to swap
these two files. So you can rename this
one to index_enty,
something like that. And then you just
rename this to index.ts. So I just have
a separate version here if you want to
enable Sentry for production monitoring
of your MCP.
And I'm not going to dive into the
details a ton here. What I did do is I
followed this guide that I'll also have
linked in the description, monitoring
your MCP servers in production. And they
actually went off of the uh GitHub ooth
example from Cloudflare and they showed
how to integrate the monitoring within
it. So really, really convenient. It
worked out super well for me. I'm really
glad I found this resource. But yeah, we
just configure Sentry. We have a
function to handle any errors that come
up. So we can have that tracing within
our Sentry dashboard. And then going
down to the bottom here, we just have to
wrap our OOTH provider within Sentry. So
it's just sentry.withentry. We're just
installing that mpm package. And then
we're wrapping our worker. This is set
up in basically the same way that we
have in our nonentry version. So we're
just kind of creating this wrapper here
that's going to watch for any errors
that happen with any of our tools and
then log those out to Sentry as well as
all the successful calls. So you can
just see at a high level everything
that's coming in, all the traces for our
MCP server. So yeah, Sentry is just an
awesome platform. I would highly
recommend using them to monitor not just
MCP servers, but also just any kind of
back-end application. I use Sentry to
monitor my AI agents in production as
well. And so I use Langfuse as my
platform more specifically to monitor
agents, but then my whole like backend
infrastructure and rag pipelines, Sentry
is a great option for that kind of
monitoring. So with that, we now have an
MCP server following all the best
practices that we can take to production
with Cloudflare. So the first thing we
have to do, we already have Wrangler set
up. So we just need to run some commands
to get things set up in our production
environment. So I've got my terminal
back up here. We need to first create a
KV or a key value store. This is we're
going to keep track of everyone that is
already authenticated with GitHub. And
so it's kind of like our mini database
to manage OOTH. And so wrangler KV
namespace create and then the name for
our KV store is going to be oath KV. So
I'm not going to run this command
because I already have this created. But
once you do, it's going to have an
output here that's going to give you
your unique KV ID. So you want to copy
that. We'll see what to do with that in
a bit. The other way that you can get
this ID once you have this KV created is
you can just go to the KV section of
storage and databases in your Cloudflare
dashboard and then you'll see it right
here. So you can just copy the ID here
as well. So take that ID then go into
your regular.json C. There'll be a
placeholder here for the KV ID that
you'll just replace with your unique
identifier. So once you have that now go
back to the readme and we are ready to
deploy. So we can just run the Wrangler
deploy. It is that easy now that we have
everything set up to deploy to
Cloudflare workers. So we will have our
MCP server running remotely in the
cloud. So Wrangler deploy and this is
actually blazing fast. It just has to
upload it to the Cloudflow worker
environment. Super super fast. And then
there we go. We now have our production
URL for our remote MCP server. It's so
so cool. We can use this to then connect
to it with cloud desktop in a little bit
or whatever MCP client you're using just
like we did when we were running it
locally. And the other way that you can
get this URL, just by the way, if you go
into the workers and pages tab here in
compute workers, we can see all of our
Cloudflare workers. Right now I just
have the MCP server right now. So you
can click on the visit link right here.
It'll say 404 not found. But this is the
our production URL. So you can copy
that. We can also, you know, do the /mcp
endpoint. It's going to say invalid
token because we're not authorized with
GitHub obviously. But yeah, this is our
URL. So you want to copy that. And then
you can go into your cloud desktop
configuration or whatever you are using
for your MCP client. And then we're just
going to replace this URL like this.
Boom. There we go. We are now good to
go. So, we're connected now to our
production MCP server. So, cool. And the
last thing we have to do before we
actually test this is we need to set up
our environment variables in production.
So, running locally, we just did things
in.dev.vars.
Now, we have to actually put these
secrets in the cloud. And so, you can
manage this in the dashboard if you want
as well. So, the way that you do that is
you click into your worker. And by the
way, you can see all of your requests
and metrics and monitoring here as well.
But if we go into settings, we can see
all of our secrets. So you can set these
manually here or you can just follow the
commands in the readme to put all of
your secrets just from the command line.
So it's just wrangler secret put and
then the name of your secret like client
ID. And then you'll just enter in the
value once you are prompted. So I'm not
going to do that here cuz I already have
that set up like you could see in my
dashboard, but you can go through with
that and you don't have to redeploy. All
of your secrets will be good to go. So
now we are ready to connect to our MCP.
So I've got my configuration all set up.
I'm going to off camera here restart my
cloud desktop. Open it back up again to
apply the latest URL. And there we go.
We can now test this out. So I'm going
to say what tables are in my database.
The same kind of query as before. What
tables are in my DB? But before I do
this, I actually had this pop up just
now. There we go. We have our
authorization request. So, this is what
I was talking about earlier where I had
a couple screenshots come up, but now
we're seeing this live. So, it's
requesting access. I'm going to click on
approve. And then I just need to
authorize my GitHub account, which I
already did. So, that page isn't popping
up here, but it'll have you connect your
GitHub account for your first time. So,
there we go. I can close out of this
now. And then I can enter in my query.
What tables are in my DB? And this is
going to look the exact same, but now
it's using a remote MCP. So, let's give
it a second here to connect. For some
reason, Claude is just taking its time.
And there we go. It's using our MCP
server. Let's see if it gets the 19
tables just like if we were running it
in development. It's taking a little bit
longer here just because it's a remote
MCP now, but still really fast. And
there we go. We got our 19 tables. And I
could even try a request here just to
try with the GitHub O the protected
tool. So I can say add a new record
to my projects
table. It can be just random values. So
we'll just try this out here using this
tool. So add a record to my projects
table and so I'll go ahead and pop up my
superb basease and I'll show you this
afterwards. But yeah, so it's inserting
into projects got random values that
it's generating here. It's requesting to
use this tool. So I'll just allow it
always. We'll see if it can add this
record to Superbase. And there we go. We
added the record. Sweet. So it is for an
AI powered recipe generator. And sure
enough, if I go into my Superbase
dashboard, I now have a project for an
AI powered recipe generator. Take a look
at that. So, we have our MCP server
fully working and we have it deployed to
Cloudflare. So, I can go in here, I can
view the metrics, I can see all the
requests coming in. So, I can refresh
this and we'll see the requests go up.
There we go. We got 27 requests now
because we have all the the whole like
handshaking process with MCP as well.
That's why there's so many requests. But
yeah, everything is working perfectly.
So that is deploying MCP servers
following best practices in a nutshell.
So there you have it. We have created an
MCP server from scratch, implemented
best practices for things like our tools
and lifespan and security and monitoring
and we've deployed it as a remote MCP
that we can now use anywhere with any
MCP client. And we have GitHub OOTH. So
it's not like people can just abuse our
MCP and you can set up things like rate
limiting and even monetize your MCP
server in this way. And I have been
talking about using AI coding assistance
throughout this video already. But the
big thing I want to say with this is you
can literally take this GitHub
repository, put it in your current
project where you want to make a new MCP
server and you could tell your cloud
code, tell your cursor, whatever to go
look at these files to understand how
I've implemented an MCP server following
all these best practices. You can even
have it reference the readme. You can
have it reference the security checklist
like we talked about earlier. You can
use all this for context. This is kind
of like context engineering like I
talked about in my last video. All of
this can be context to provide really
good examples to the AI coding
assistant. So it can knock out any MCP
server that you want to make. And you
can even do things like switch from
GitHub to Google for your OOTH. And so
definitely check out my last video on
context engineering if you want an
example of a process where you can
incorporate what I just talked about. I
don't want to cover that all from
scratch right here because I just
covered that on my channel. So
definitely check that out if you are
interested. But yeah, with that, you now
have what it takes to build production
ready MCP servers that are bulletproof.
And so I hope that you found this
template super super useful. If you did,
I would really appreciate a like and a
subscribe. Definitely a lot more content
coming for MCP and deploying agents to
production in general. And so with that,
I will see you in the next